Joseph D. Schroers Jr

Richmond, VA joeyschroers@gmail.com 540.290.8138

SUMMARY

Challenge-seeking Microsoft Azure Data Engineer with 4 years of experience in the consulting field; projects primarily in the Consumer Packaged Goods and State & Local Government industries. Looking to use experience and technical knowledge to solve problems and/or build solutions that will drive insights to help make business decisions.

Data Engineering, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Data Science, Consumer Packaged Goods (Supply Chain & Manufacturing), State & Local Government (Workers Compensation)

TECHNOLOGY

Languages: SQL, Python, R

Resources: Azure Databricks, Azure Data Factory, Azure Data Lake, Azure Functions, Azure Machine Learning, Azure

SQL, Azure DevOps

Additional Technologies: git, Spark, Microsoft Power BI, Tableau

Fortune 200 Consumer Packaged Goods Company, Richmond, VA

WORK EXPERIENCE

CapTech Ventures, Inc., Richmond, VA

Senior Data & Cloud Engineering Consultant

Data Engineer

Developed PySpark/SQL notebooks on a Databricks platform to create and load curated datasets within an Enterprise Data Model

- Employed best practices for Databricks such as utilizing Delta tables, implementing a dynamic logging framework and notebook format, and structuring notebooks to function as a delta load based on columns within source tables
- Optimized Production deployments and reduced ricks by developing processes to automate tasks, eliminating data downtime, and logging output files
- Mentored two data engineers by assisting with onboarding, providing knowledge transfer, and offering guidance of Databricks and Python/SQL/Spark best practices

CapTech Ventures, Inc., Richmond, VA

Aug 2019 - Dec 2022

Jul 2019 - Present

Apr 2021 - Present

Lead Data Engineer

- Utilized ETL processes by creating an Azure Data Factory environment that egressed Workday and Salesforce data for ingestion into an Azure SQL database
- Automated the build and deployment of an Azure SOL database and an Azure Data Factory environment both using Azure DevOps Pipelines
- Developed a bipartite matching algorithm to optimally match consultants to client projects

New York State Workers Compensation Board, Richmond, VA / Schenectady, NY

Aug 2019 - Apr 2021

- Data Analyst
 - Owned and became a subject matter expert on four Workers Compensation Board processes along with
 - Led discussions with clients to gather data requirements and to define source-to-target mapping documents
 - Utilized Visual Basic to create a Microsoft Access form that tracked mappings and transformations needed for data migration
 - Developed templates and contributed to documents that aimed to standardize processes

CERTIFICATIONS

Azure Database Administrator Associate - Microsoft	Mar 2022 - Mar 2023
Azure Data Fundamentals - Microsoft	Apr 2021
Azure AI Fundamentals - Microsoft	Jun 2021

EDUCATION

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, VA May 2019 Bachelor of Science - Computational Modeling and Data Analytics

STRENGTHS

Consistency, Positivity, Discipline, Includer, Restorative